

MULTIMEDIA ENGINEER

Campinas - São Paulo, Brazil

□ (+55) 19 99612 2927 | ■ mafda13@gmail.com | 🌴 mafda.github.io/ | 🖫 mafda | 🛅 mafda

about me_

I have worked in the digital media industry in tasks such as web design and image and video editing. Also, I have experience as an academic researcher, focusing mainly on areas related to augmented reality and machine learning, among others, like computer graphics, computer vision, and image processing.

My interests cover from interface design, focusing on UI/UX, to web and mobile applications. Without leaving aside the back-end development. I think that having an understanding of how the full-stack is composed, the whole development process is more fluent. My goal is to become a full-stack developer!

I consider myself a creative, committed, and responsible person. I'm an enthusiast of self-learning, and I feel excited in front of big new challenges.

skills

Code Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, PHP. **Design** Photoshop, Gimp, Illustrator, Maya, 3ds Max.

Dev Bootstrap, Jekyll, ReactJS, React Native, NodeJS, Django.

Tools Command Line, Vim, Git, Markdown, Latex, OpenCV, Pandas, TensorFlow, Keras, Jupyter/Collab Notebook, Docker.

education

PhD student in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Campinas — SP, Brazil

UNIVERSITY OF CAMPINAS — UNICAMP

Since 2015

 Thesis: 'Occlusion treatment in objects tracking for augmented reality systems'. Advisor: Prof. José Mario De Martino, Ph.D.

MSc. in Mechanical Engineering

Campinas — SP, Brazil

UNIVERSITY OF CAMPINAS — UNICAMP

2012 — 2014

• Dissertation: 'Development of a hybrid localization system for autonomous navigation of ground vehicles in a simulated environment'. Advisor: Prof. Janito Vaqueiro Ferreira, Ph.D.

Multimedia Engineering

Bogotá, Colombia

Nueva Granada Military University — UMNG

2004 — 2009

• Thesis: 'Development of a virtual an object of learning for management training of animal models in research processes'.

Advisor: Prof. Germán Andrés Garnica.

experience_

DCA — FEEC, University of Campinas

Campinas — SP, Brazill

RESEARCHER

01/2015 — 06/2015

- Explore the performance and potential of markerless tracking in Vuforia Augmented Reality SDK.
- Develop a demo on mobile devices, as an auxiliary guide of an underwater oil exploration device.

Parexton The Web Design co.

Freelance

WEB DESIGNER

01/2010 — 12/2014

- Design, development, and maintenance of websites with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Development of SEO strategies with Google Analytics.
- · Corporate image design and brand with Photoshop.

languagues_____

		Listening	Reading	Speaking	Writing
Spanish	Mother tongue	Fluent	Fluent	Fluent	Fluent
Portuguese		Advanced	Advanced	Advanced	Advanced
English		Intermediate	Intermediate	Basic	Intermediate

courses & certifications _____

WEB DEVELOPER

2020 P	Python and Django Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp, Online	Udemy
---------------	---	-------

AGILE METHODOLOGIES

2019	Gestão Ágil com SCRUM	, Online	Jdem ₂	У
------	-----------------------	----------	-------------------	---

MACHINE LEARNING

2019	Introduction to machine learning & deep learning in python, Online	Udemy
2019	Master computer vision opencv3 in python & machine learning, Online	Udemy
2018	Zero to deep learning with python and keras, Online	Udemy
2018	Redes neurais artificiais em python, Online	Udemy

3DSTUDIO MAX

2010	Materials, hair, cloth & character rigging, Bogotá, Colombia	Autodesk
2010	Character modeling, Bogotá, Colombia	Autodesk
2010	Advertising animation, Bogotá, Colombia	Autodesk

publications _____

- RUIZ, M. F. R., De Martino, J., Pelaquim, J. "Augmented reality applied for the inspection and pre-installation testing of underwater oil production device". *IV Congreso Internacional de Multimedia*. Bogotá Colombia.
- 2015 RUIZ, M. F. R., Ferreira, J. V., Miranda Neto, A., "Referenced Localization Method Based on the Recognition of Key Objects from a Digital Map". IV Congreso Internacional de Multimedia. Bogotá Colombia.
- **2014** RUIZ, M. F. R., Ferreira, J. V., "Navegação sem condutor, mas segura". In *Jornal da Unicamp*, page 11. Campinas SP, Brazil.
- 2014 RUIZ, M. F. R., "Desenvolvimento de um sistema de localização híbrido para navegação autônoma de veículos terrestres em ambiente simulado". Master's thesis, University of Campinas.